<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-23T15:56:10+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sam Healer</title><subtitle>Software developer. Erstwhile comedian. Cultural omnivore.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Some inadvertently wise advice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/advice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some inadvertently wise advice" /><published>2020-05-28T19:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-28T19:24:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/advice/">&lt;p&gt;For the last year, I’ve been mentoring our intern on our team, Harry - an immensely rewarding experience which I’ll be repeating with one of our new interns when they join next month. For various reasons above my pay grade, Harry was given a project he shouldn’t have been given - a project that would be widely used in production by actual consumers. Oh, and he’d be the only person working on it. Fortunately for us, Harry is remarkably technologically adept and has ably risen to the challenges he’s encountered over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, he asked if we could have a chat, because he was worried he wasn’t living up to the expectations he’d set himself, that he felt he should have had this done a while ago and it had been weighing on him that he hadn’t finished yet. This is something I think all software engineers feel, and probably most of us do in life just generally. Lord knows I’ve been feeling like that for the last 9 months or so at work with my own project, had felt like that with stand up for the last few months of it, and have still been feeling like that for personal stuff the last couple months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advice I thought sounded good in the moment was this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Get the project “finished”, whatever that looks like. Learn practical, specific lessons from it (“I should have been updating the design document more often” rather than “I screwed the design up totally”). Reflect on the things you’ve done well that you’d notice as an outside observer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And actually I think there’s something really valuable in there. Most of us, narcissists aside, are able to notice their own flaws, often to a self-paralysing extent (hi!). And of the “most of us”, most of us are able to at least try to work on those flaws, and sometimes we improve, and sometimes we fall back, but we’re conscious of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the time, though, fewer people are really able to identify and embrace the things they’re good at, or the things they’ve done well. Trying to fix the bad stuff is easy, but god it wears you down. Every effort to improve your flaws is just another reminder that they exist in the first place, and it’s no wonder we give up new year’s resolutions so easily. They’re never about just keeping or doing more of the good stuff, it’s almost always trying to undo some bad habit. And so those good attributes flounder, or plateau, or atrophy. You miss out on the positive feedback loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told Harry that I think the ability to both improve your flaws and actively build on your strengths is the surest indicator of going on to become a top engineer. It’s probably true in general. I hope it is. I’m always staggered by my ability to give good advice that I don’t take, and I’m going to make more of an effort to actually listen to myself this time. After all, giving good advice is one of my most positive attributes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">For the last year, I’ve been mentoring our intern on our team, Harry - an immensely rewarding experience which I’ll be repeating with one of our new interns when they join next month. For various reasons above my pay grade, Harry was given a project he shouldn’t have been given - a project that would be widely used in production by actual consumers. Oh, and he’d be the only person working on it. Fortunately for us, Harry is remarkably technologically adept and has ably risen to the challenges he’s encountered over the last year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Things I hadn’t appreciated I possess…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/possessions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things I hadn't appreciated I possess..." /><published>2020-02-29T19:36:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-29T19:36:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/possessions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/possessions/">&lt;p&gt;…as discovered during the process of moving flat for the first time in three and a half years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An never-used Google Glass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No, seriously, too many books. Like, too many in the flat I had to myself, let alone the smaller flat I now share.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to understand the Japanese word “tsundoku” - to have the habit of buying books at a faster rate than one reads them - and yet the inability to stop myself fulfilling this prophecy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My old flatmate Phoebe’s blanket, so bequeathed to me 5 years ago now&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pretty much every ticket I’ve ever bought from the Watershed in the last 7 years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A number of signed setlists from artists including Philip Selway(!), Our Girl, and All We Are&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Old copies of the Metro with lyric fragments scribbled illegibly on them during long bus journeys on the 70 to and from work in the old days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insufficient bedding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A real lack of visual space perception&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thirteen brand new washing up sponges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Five extension leads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two hot water bottles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A mug from when I went to see The Muppets at the O2 that has never been used but was still carefully wrapped in newspaper to survive the journey to this flat, such that it may continue to not be used in peace, not pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A microwave. It doesn’t really occur to you that you actually &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; a microwave until you move into a flat that already has one and you’re struck by the existential terror of what must become of your microwave. You’ve got to take it. Where do you put it? Can you sell it? Who would want it? Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A collection of recipes clipped from magazines by my well-meaning but ultimately optimistic mother&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That being said, my own brownie recipe, perfected over much trial and error but gone unused for some time now&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A box of Cheerios in the cupboard from the time of the last Star Wars film. No, not Rise Of Skywalker. The previous one. Yeah.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barack Oblobblehead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An innate desire or need to live with other people, even if most of that time is spent in a room alone, because as introverted as you can be and as great as it is to spent time by yourself, other people are great too. Even better if they have a dog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bottle of Khazakstani vodka called Black Gold. It is neither of those two adjectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">…as discovered during the process of moving flat for the first time in three and a half years:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A brief round-up of recent literature</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/literature/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A brief round-up of recent literature" /><published>2020-02-23T21:19:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-23T21:19:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/literature</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/literature/">&lt;p&gt;I’ll level with you, gang, I have no idea what to write about this week, so to fill the void until next weekend when hopefully I’ll have actually thought about something and my mental bandwidth will have been allocated back to the usual things rather than the big move, here are some of my favourite books I’ve read so far this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Books Sam has read in 2020: a thread. Hopefully. I always start this kind of thing with the best of intentions and then by February it is forgotten. But I am nothing if not eternally optimistic, so here we go&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sam Healer (@anewthought) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anewthought/status/1212817787447660546?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 2, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Topeka School by Ben Lerner - I am every college-educated white 20-something man you’ve ever read disparaging Twitter threads about. Some of it, admittedly, I can help, but other bits I can’t. I love Radiohead, and Stewart Lee, and &lt;em&gt;Annie Hall&lt;/em&gt; - sue me. I cannot help but appreciate more those pieces of art that are, for want of a better word, “clever”. And &lt;em&gt;The Topeka School&lt;/em&gt; is that. It is incredible to watch Lerner weave through so many turns of phrase and pieces of imagery and thematic links, and then bring them back again and again in different lighting, in new forms and new perspectives, applied to the trivial and to the most important. The same melodies reused and rearranged to become new songs altogether. And at its heart, a soon to be college-educated white 18-something man who is broken, a little bit, but doesn’t know why; an acknowledgement that he isn’t the only one; and an attempt to understand quite how we got to the point where that’s the case. One of the best books I’ve read in about 10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone Who Will Love You In All Your Damaged Glory by Raphael Bob-Waksberg - I knew from the moment I heard that Bob-Waksberg was publishing a collection of short stories that this would be very much my jam. Best known as the creator of BoJack Horseman (which, for what it’s worth, is the kind of show that I’m eternally grateful for), Bob-Waksberg brings exactly the humour, melancholia, romance, and emotion to short stories as he does to an animated sitcom about a depressed horse. Longer stories are interlaced with more form-breaking pieces that exist somewhere between prose and poetry, as if floating above the surface before revealing just how heavy they are. I’ve thought a lot about these pieces and these stories since, not least &lt;em&gt;Rufus&lt;/em&gt;, a touching story from a dog’s perspective. Because even in print, the best way to tell us how we really feel is anthropomorphism.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This Is How You Lose The Time War by Amal El-Mohtar &amp;amp; Max Gladstone - I’ve been maintaining a Twitter thread of all the books I read this year (see above), and the thing that really strikes me when trying to summarise these books for that is noticing just exactly what I took from them. In &lt;em&gt;This Is How You Lose The Time War&lt;/em&gt;, two time travellers working for rival factions leave each other letters as they foil each other’s plans, slowly but surely falling in love. Through this, the novel explores the long, slow act of coming to know someone intimately; the fear of opening yourself up, of earnestness. But it also contemplates, both implicitly and at one point explicitly, the time travelling nature of letters: they are written in the past to be read in the future, the reaction to the writing happening so far away from the writing itself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interior Chinatown by Charles Yu - Yu is one of my favourite short story writers - his previous collection, &lt;em&gt;Sorry Please Thank You&lt;/em&gt;, is astonishing - but I first discovered him through his debut novel &lt;em&gt;How To Live Safely In A Science Fictional Universe&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Interior Chinatown&lt;/em&gt;, his second novel, is intriguing in how it simultaneously diverges from Yu’s usual focuses but yet is unmistakably him. Yu has always seemed fascinated by the trappings of science fiction and fantasy as a way of exploring the way we try to find our place in a world that increasingly resembles the sci-fi we used to read. &lt;em&gt;Interior Chinatown&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t really tread that path, as a novel concerned with being an Asian man in America today, but more broadly about belonging and the roles we allow ourselves to play. But through its script-like format and a relentless need to push the medium, to refract and reflect its premise until all gimmicks really just fall away and the truth of it is laid bare, self-evident, Yu once again achieves the exceptional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Boy, The Mole, The Fox &amp;amp; The Horse by Charlie Mackesy - this is the kind of sentimental work that is easy to dismiss or be snobbish about. It can be derided as easy and cloying and vapid. But I don’t think it is, really. I think sometimes you need to hear the things that might come across that way, because sometimes “cleverness” and anthropomorphism and concept and medium just get in the way. A series of illustrations, beautifully rendered, of a boy, a mole, a fox, and (yes) a horse as they come to terms with knowing each other. I decided to buy a print of one of them - it took a while to narrow down just which one, but in the end it was the one that the moment I read it, I took a photo of it and made it my phone’s homescreen. Just because it’s a reminder that people love you. What more can a good book do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I’ll level with you, gang, I have no idea what to write about this week, so to fill the void until next weekend when hopefully I’ll have actually thought about something and my mental bandwidth will have been allocated back to the usual things rather than the big move, here are some of my favourite books I’ve read so far this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Up in the clouds</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/clouds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Up in the clouds" /><published>2020-02-02T12:36:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T12:36:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/clouds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/clouds/">&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts that have occurred to me about the process of air travel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The twists and turns of duty free just past security are identical in every airport, down to the ordering and placement of booze, then perfume, then a hard right angle at the LEGO which is still over-priced even without VAT, then the Toblerones and Milka chocolate, until you open out - a seamless transition - into the arena of the inevitable W H Smiths, Burger Kings, and Wetherspoons and/or Wetherspoons knock-offs (which are, of course, preferable - all the benefits of a microwaved full English with at least a more subtle form of nationalism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will only occur to you approximately half an hour before a flight, whilst sat at the gate, thousand yard stare fixed to your face, what the inevitable demographic of that flight will be. If you’re heading to, say, Orlando, you may well have not realised until the last minute just how many of the passengers will be overexcited children going to Disneyland, although rest assured that their attire and hyperactivity both at the gate and as they run down the aisle of the plane will make themselves obvious to all concerned. You wonder if just slightly sticking your leg out and tripping them would get the attention of the parent busily ignoring them with the latest Terminator film on a tiny screen, but somehow you doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best situation to be in the day after Dry January ends is an altitude of approximately 36,000 feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An non-hack observation about airplane food: when presented with two meal options, the pasta one will always sound more appealing than the non-pasta option, and as such you will always opt for it, but will always be more underwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All grand plans to catch up on books, and podcasts, and music, and films crumble on contact with the reality of a 9 and a half hour plane journey, spent mostly watching the flight map and wondering how you’ve never realised just how long 6 hours can be when it’s only so far been 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every plane journey, regardless of origin or destination, observes the same basic route. A quiet calm because you know that, statistically, flying is very safe. A slightly bumpy take-off that makes you believe that, yes, this is the time you’re going to crash and die. An innate curiosity about how and when, exactly, your friends, coworkers, and loved ones will be made aware of your demise, and a deep sadness that you never got to say the things you should have said to them. A look to the bright side, an acceptance, a freedom - that todo list at work won’t need dealing with anymore; that letter from the council now needs no reply; the decisions and actions you were having to make which made you so anxious now no longer affect you. Finally, a safe landing with a slight sense of disappointment that you survived - the bills still need paying, the work sat on your desk remains yours, those decisions still need taking. But, hey, you’re in Orlando now, so might as well make the most of it. Disneyland, anyone?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Some thoughts that have occurred to me about the process of air travel:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’ve got a golden ticket…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/golden-ticket/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I've got a golden ticket..." /><published>2020-01-26T12:25:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T12:25:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/golden-ticket</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/golden-ticket/">&lt;p&gt;It’s funny those little things that you sometimes realise you define yourself by, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m good at buying tickets. Like, very good. Put it this way - if I have tried to buy tickets to a gig, no matter how immediately everyone agrees it’s going to sell out, I have managed to get them. Granted, I have never attempted to get Glastonbury tickets, you suckers are on your own for that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My crowning glory in this was all the way back in 2016. Radiohead (of course it was Radiohead, what else did you expect from me?) were back and playing their first shows in the UK for four years. In 2012, they’d played two nights at the O2 and a night at Manchester Arena. 60,000 tickets for the whole of the UK, instant sell out. Back to 2016, their first gigs in four years, just three nights at the Roundhouse, so about 9000 tickets total. At this point, Radiohead had been the band that meant the most to me in the world for about 8 years. I had never seen them live, and boy did it seem impossible that I was going to be doing so this time. Did I get those tickets? Well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;cy&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ohmygodohmygodohmygodohmygodohmygodohmygodohmygod I&amp;#39;m going to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/radiohead?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@radiohead&lt;/a&gt; live aaaaaaahhhhhhhhhhhhh&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sam Healer (@anewthought) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anewthought/status/710045946478985216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah I did. That first half of 2016 was one of the happiest times in my life, and in amongst that was this, seeing Radiohead in the smallest feasible venue I’d ever get to see them, second row from the rail, Jonny Greenwood’s side. If you had told me that I’d never get another highly sought after ticket again in my life, I’d probably have taken it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not the case. I’ve been to see Radiohead again since, I’ve been to see Thom Yorke multiple times since, I was there at the first LCD Soundsystem show at Alexandra Palace in 2017, at Bon Iver, and The National (so many times now), and The Antlers playing Hospice acoustically at Union Chapel, and Sufjan Stevens at the Colston Hall, and so many more. I have texted friends to confirm I’ve bought tickets less than a minute after they’ve gone on sale, before they could even load the queue to try to buy tickets themselves. I know exactly what I’m doing now. It’s an art, it’s a science, it’s a preternatural ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t realise how much that meant to me until this week. By all accounts, the gig I was buying for should have been a piece of piss - 60,000 tickets total, I’ve beaten shorter odds than that time and time again, but suddenly I realised that I’d so built up this idea of myself as being able to do this that I was so stressed it by it collapsing at this point. Of course in the end, I had the tickets bought and informed those who needed informing by 9.31am (and was even able to dial into the meeting I’d intended to miss to get tickets in the first place as if nothing had happened).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to think you’re defined by the big things. The obvious things. And there’s no denying that they do define you, in a sense - I’ll always be a computer geek, a guitarist, the short blond one, the insufferably but broadly well-meaningly clever one - all things I’m proud of. But really, the small things can weigh an awful lot more. I know one day I’ll fail to get tickets to something. I’m almost looking forward to finding out what that gig is, which enemy finally fell me. But whatever it is, I’ll always have this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Up in the clouds. Can&amp;#39;t stop grinning. I am dancing, freaking out &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/uDUMFD1rda&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/uDUMFD1rda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sam Healer (@anewthought) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anewthought/status/736313607877693440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 27, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">It’s funny those little things that you sometimes realise you define yourself by, isn’t it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Five films from the last decade</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/five-films/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five films from the last decade" /><published>2020-01-19T10:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-19T10:04:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/five-films</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/five-films/">&lt;p&gt;I am not my rosy self, left my roses on my shelf. Here are five films from the last decade. I can’t tell you these are by some objective measure the five “best” films of the last 10 years. I can’t necessarily tell you they’re my favourite five films of the last 10 years. But these are the five films which I think are some of the most personally important films to me from the last 10 years, and some attempt to explain why they are, even if not what they are. And that’s got to mean something, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-monster-calls-2016-dir-ja-boyana&quot;&gt;A Monster Calls (2016, dir. J.A. Boyana)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not ashamed to cry at films, by any stretch of the imagination. I think it’s fair to say everyone has their own little touchpoints, the buttons a film can press to kick it off more than usual, and boy does A Monster Calls do that for me. The first time I saw it, I went in blind to a preview screening at Bath Film Festival, knowing only that it was going to be a sad one. And as I sat in a toilet cubicle in the Bath Odeon afterwards simply to gather myself together again, I reflected on the fact that this was by far the most I’d ever cried at a film (as an adult, as I do vividly remember the peril in Barney’s Great Adventure being quite distressing as a young child). When it was released properly a few months later, I went to see it again, feeling fully prepared for the experience, thinking that knowing exactly why I cried throughout the back half of it and the exact moments it would be the worst would somehow mean I wouldn’t cry as much. If anything, I cried even more the second time around. I cried at the same points in the Bristol Old Vic’s beautiful stage adaptation in 2018. I am fairly certain I’m going to cry at the same points any time I watch it from now on. I look forward to doing so again immensely, hopefully soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-such-a-beautiful-day-2012-dir-don-hertzfeldt&quot;&gt;It’s Such A Beautiful Day (2012, dir. Don Hertzfeldt)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite film of the last decade. At 62 minutes long, Hertzfeldt packs in more meaning and depth than most directors achieve in their entire careers. The darkly funny and often heartbreaking story of a stick figure named Bill, It’s Such A Beautiful Day features some of the most narratively and cinematically effective in-camera animation effects I’ve ever seen. Comprising three slightly re-edited short films into a single triptych, the films tackles big topics through absurd imagery until the truth can’t be ignored any more and confronts it with great poise. It’s such a beautiful day, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-perks-of-being-a-wallflower-2012-dir-stephen-chbosky&quot;&gt;The Perks Of Being A Wallflower (2012, dir. Stephen Chbosky)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“we accept the love we think we deserve”&lt;/em&gt;. Well, fuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever spoken to me about films for long enough, I’ll have told you my strong conviction that the context in which you watch a film cannot be separated from your perception of the film itself. Case in point, The Perks Of Being A Wallflower, watched for the first time in the Bristol SU as part of a mental health awareness week, in my second term of uni, still scared and still homesick. I’m under no illusions that this film has flaws, but to me it is perfect. I cannot listen to Come On Eileen without thinking of the school dance scnee, cannot imagine any feeling of love as much as Charlie seeing Sam smile, cannot hope for any greater understanding of why I identify with Charlie so. I’ve rewatched it only the once, late at night at the end of my university career in an empty flat and was a wreck by the end of it, in the best kind of way. Sometimes it’s ok to be happy being sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-ghost-story-2017-dir-david-lowery&quot;&gt;A Ghost Story (2017, dir. David Lowery)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes, the “Rooney Mara eating pie for 5 minutes straight” film. Look beyond that and you’ll find a film that covers so much more. The passing of time, grief, impermanence, depression, and love. All with a silent protagonist of a ghost in a sheet, the most conventional depiction that you never actually see, unstuck in time and forced to confront the life he had. Shot in Academy ratio with an exceptional eye for depth of vision, Lowery tells a story that achieves great depths both intellectually and emotionally, and more importantly without ever feeling like those are two separate aims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;carol-2015-dir-todd-haynes&quot;&gt;Carol (2015, dir. Todd Haynes)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a shot in Carol, towards the beginning, of Rooney Mara (second appearance on this list, I realise now) working in a department store at Christmas, Santa hat on, shot in sumptuously grainy Super 16mm. I have never forgotten that shot. It is almost acceptable as a dictionary definition of beauty, both in subject and composition. That is almost as true of the film as a whole. The relationship between Carol and Therese is so carefully and lovingly depicted on all accounts, from Mara and Cate Blanchett’s portrayals to the writing, the direction, the cinematography, the editing, everything. Above almost all else, though, is Alexandre Desplat’s score, especially the main theme, a piece of music that I sang to myself all the way home from the Watershed to make sure I didn’t forget it by the time I could find a copy of the score. Let’s end this ramble of a blog post with it, at least provide something of value:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/awk0YahlOcA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I am not my rosy self, left my roses on my shelf. Here are five films from the last decade. I can’t tell you these are by some objective measure the five “best” films of the last 10 years. I can’t necessarily tell you they’re my favourite five films of the last 10 years. But these are the five films which I think are some of the most personally important films to me from the last 10 years, and some attempt to explain why they are, even if not what they are. And that’s got to mean something, right?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Music</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/making-music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Music" /><published>2020-01-12T10:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-12T10:45:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/making-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/making-music/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing songs for about 9 years now. I’ve been recording songs for about 7 years now. The songs have been passable for about 6 years now. I’ve dared to record vocals for about 4 years now (not that any of those recordings have seen the light of day). This was, for quite a while, my main creative outlets and I’d built up quite a body of work, if admittedly unreleased. But then another creative outlet opened itself up a couple of years ago, and I only have a limited mental budget for this kind of thing in my life, so the songs fell by the wayside somewhat. And then James Acaster came along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Acaster is possibly my favourite comedian, a very nice person, and unrelatedly really knows his dessert places in New York. I was very excited for the publication of his second book, Perfect Sound Whatever, last year, and devoured it in a couple of days on release. The book is in part an examination of music released in 2016 and in part an examination of a breakdown he went through in 2017. It is an excellent piece of writing on both counts, and one which contains the following passage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/68648492_361239248141556_8522284295832731648_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;68648492_361239248141556_8522284295832731648_n&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immediately sent this photo on reading it to my friend and former flatmate Phoebe, whom I had at one point been in what could loosely be termed as a “band” with. In university we had played three open mic nights in halls at uni - two Radiohead songs and Fairytale of New York for Christmas - and recorded ourselves doing covers of such esteemed songs as We Are Golden by Mika and, of course, Yeah by Usher. We named ourselves Bastions of Integrity - what else would you call a band that almost exclusively played Radiohead covers at open mic nights? - and kept it alive through stupid fake names of albums and songs and an entire history of the band. Despite never actually writing a song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But reading that passage in James’s book spurred something in me. I followed his advice, and asked Phoebe if we were going to make a Bastions of Integrity album. Of course we were, came the response. Our initial steps were trepidatious, a certain uncertainty in sharing lyrics and musical ideas, a quite personal thing, but this has ultimately been good for me, at least - I can’t speak for Phoebe but I imagine she feels somewhat the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to make an album and then release it. We started on this, with a number of songs in the works, until we reached mid-December and decided that the only sensible thing to do was to release a Christmas song. Our most collaborative effort to date, Wherever You Are At Christmas was released into the world on the 23rd of December, literally the morning it was finished. 20 bucks to Distrokid later and somehow we existed on Spotify, and iTunes, and Apple Music, and even Tidal - Tidal! For all twelve remaining users. I still listen to it and find flaws, but honestly I’m incredibly proud of that song and the fact that I got over a lot of insecurities and actually put it out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what remains for 2020? I think the plan has shifted to a series of EPs rather than a single album - having paid for the Distrokid subscription, we might as well make the most of it, and forcing ourselves to actually finish 4 or 5 songs at a time is probably much better for our discipline. In the same way that I don’t imagine anyone is actually reading this, I don’t imagine anyone is ever going to actually listen to the music we put out (this is why I don’t look at the Bandcamp stats), but I think there’s something to be said about the act of putting it out there. So with any luck, this time next year, Bastions of Integrity will have released 12 or so more songs. Scary to think about. Let’s check back in then, yeah? Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I’ve been writing songs for about 9 years now. I’ve been recording songs for about 7 years now. The songs have been passable for about 6 years now. I’ve dared to record vocals for about 4 years now (not that any of those recordings have seen the light of day). This was, for quite a while, my main creative outlets and I’d built up quite a body of work, if admittedly unreleased. But then another creative outlet opened itself up a couple of years ago, and I only have a limited mental budget for this kind of thing in my life, so the songs fell by the wayside somewhat. And then James Acaster came along.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Resolutions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resolutions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resolutions" /><published>2020-01-05T20:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-05T20:16:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resolutions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resolutions/">&lt;p&gt;For reasons that can only put down to being an educated white male with simultaneously too much and too little self-esteem, I once again feel the need to start a new year by beginning to blog again. And that’s why we’re here. Hello. I thought I’d start by talking about new year’s resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s heartening that we, as a society, treat a new year as a chance to be different, become better. And yes, it never quite goes to plan, but we try nonetheless in our own big and small ways. It’s hard to tell which ones will stick; I gave up drinking Coke in January 2017 and haven’t had a sip of the stuff in three years, and you try telling anyone who knew me that was going to happen. And so what if they don’t stick? Even if you only stick out out for a few weeks, or months, it’s a sign that you want to change and a sign that you can try. That’s one hell of a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these are my resolutions this year, for the most part. I might mess ‘em all up by the end of February, but it’s worth a go, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do things for the right reasons&lt;/strong&gt;. Oh, this is tricky. isn’t it? I’ve been thinking a lot recently about why I think and behave in the ways I do, trying to be conscious of why I do certain things for the wrong reasons. Why I say yes to some things even though what I want out of it would be bad for me, why I say no to some things even though they’d be better for me. And so that’s something I’m trying to be aware of this year. To make sure I put myself in the right situations for the right reasons, and take myself out of the wrong situations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep getting fitter&lt;/strong&gt;. I lost about 8kg in the last four months of 2019, through actually exercising properly and watching both what and how much I eat. Yeah, turns out it’s literally that easy, who knew? I’ll be honest, I’m still not happy with how I look yet. And I’m aware that’s a slippery slope, but see resolution #1 to be assured that I’m not doing this to look “ripped” or to impress anyone or anything like that, but to be happier in myself and my long-term sustainable health. I can run 5k on the treadmill multiple times a week now, and that’s ridiculous considering where I was this time last year. So I just need to keep that up, keep up the better diet, and not let it become all-encompassing. Which, after Christmas this year, I can promise you won’t be an issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use and keep up a bullet journal&lt;/strong&gt;. I do have a slightly fetisishtic love of organisation which does not apply to how messy my life is, both physically and indeed at times metaphorically. After countless apps and websites, I’m turning to a structured form of paper-based event management and task tracking, with the primary aim being to get all the stuff that I overthink about and keep rattling around my brain out of there and onto the page instead.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular blogging and more regular diarying&lt;/strong&gt;. The blogging won’t last. But the private diary might. I regret not doing it more in my more formative years, because the scraps I do have from school and the beginning of university are fascinating to look back on now (to me and literally no one else, obviously). A brief diary entry at the end of the day, just to jog the memories of little details that make up life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily happiness/gratitude post-its&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the most wanky sounding one, and I’m aware that that’s saying something after those four. But a friend of mine did this last year and reported success, so I’m giving it a go. The idea as I understand it (or at the very least, the way I’m doing it even if I’ve completely misunderstood it) is to write down on a post-it note each day something that’s made you happy or greateful that day, fold it up, and stick it somewhere. I’m sure a lot of the value is in the act of forcing yourself to think about that each day, but the idea of opening them up at the end of the year is also kind of funny to think about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there we go. Five resolutions that I hadn’t really fully thought through until writing this post, so I guess it’s been useful for me even if not particularly interesting to you. Who am I kidding, you’re not reading to this point. I reckon there’s only three more entries this year before I forget anyway, so no worries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>samhealer</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">For reasons that can only put down to being an educated white male with simultaneously too much and too little self-esteem, I once again feel the need to start a new year by beginning to blog again. And that’s why we’re here. Hello. I thought I’d start by talking about new year’s resolutions.</summary></entry></feed>